（ナルト）死んでたやつが
ひっかき回すな！
Dead men shouldn't go around
messing things up!
おぉ～！
（マダラ）うちは返し。
Uchiha Reflection.
（ガイ）くっ…。
俺が八尾と九尾をやる。
I'll get the Eight and Nine Tails.
オビト　お前はこいつらをやれ。
Obito, you take down those two.
なにっ　させるか！
- What?!
- You're not getting away!
（カカシ）オビト　お前に何があったんだ？
どうして　あんなやつと？
Obito...
What happened to you?
Why would you join up with him?
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
((遅いぞ　オビト。
（ミナト）やっと来たね　キミがオビトか。
You're late, Obito!
You're finally here...
（リン）待ってたよ。
（オビト）はぁ　ギリか。
You must be Obito.
We've been waiting for you.
大遅刻だよ。
Barely made it...
You're really late.
もう自己紹介は終わっている。
あとはキミだけ。
We've already introduced ourselves.
You're the only one left!
俺は火影になる。　うちはオビトだ。
I'm going to be the Hokage!
My name's Obito Uchiha!
んでもって　俺の火影岩には
トレードマークのゴーグルと→
For my Great Stone Face,
make sure my trademark goggles
and Sharingan are nicely carved out!
更に
写輪眼もしっかり彫ってもらう。
それで他里に
にらみをきかせてやんのだ！
So I can glare over
the neighboring lands!
はぁ。
（オビト）写輪眼でメンチきってる→
I'll scare the hell out of them
with my Sharingan stare...
俺の火影岩にビビって
ここには手を出さねえようにな。
and no one will dare
attack our village!
そんなのは火影になって
写輪眼を開眼してから注文しろ。
Rattle off your instructions
after you become the Hokage
and activate your Sharingan.
だいたいゴーグルしてたら
写輪眼は彫れないだろ。
Besides, how can they carve
the Sharingan
if you're wearing goggles?
（オビト）ゴーグルの上から彫れば
いいだろうが！
They can carve it out
over my goggles!
それだと目が飛び出てる
みたいになるね。　フフッ。
Then it will look like your eyeballs
are popping out.
とにかく　俺と同じ夢を持ってる
部下ができて嬉しいよ。
Anyway... I'm happy that
someone on this team
shares my dream.
今日からキミの上司になるミナトだ。
よろしく。
I'm Minato. From today,
I'll be your superior.
(おぅ！))
I'm glad to meet you!
Yeah!
《オビト：ミナト先生。
Minato Sensei...
もう　こんなとこは…。
All of this...
こんな世界は…》
This world...
《オビト：どうでもいいんだよ！》
- None of it matters anymore!
んなわけにいくか　ボケ！
I'm not gonna let
that happen, idiot!
俺ってば　四代目火影の息子だぞ。
I'm the son of
the Fourth Hokage, you know!
てめえの口車なんかにはのらねえ。
I'm not gonna fall for your talk!
そうか。
人柱力の本体だからと→
I see.
I was going easy on you
大目に見てやったが…
なら　手加減はできんぞ。
because you were
the actual Jinchuriki, not a clone.
but if that's how you feel,
I won't hold back on you!
かつて　俺の九尾を縛り上げた
柱間の木龍だ。
This is Hashirama's wooden dragon,
which he used to hold down
my Nine Tails long ago.
（キラービー）
やっぱマダラは　ムチャクチャ強ぇな。
Madara really is crazy powerful.
それこそ
やりがいがあるというもの。
That's what makes him
worth fighting.
あんたは　強がりが強ぇな。
Your tough guy act is crazy solid.
こっちだって
ゾンビ相手に手加減はしねえ。
I'm not going to hold back
against a zombie either!
死んでんだからな。
Since you're already dead!
なぜだ？
なぜ　マダラのようなやつと。
Why?!
Why ally yourself with someone
like Madara?
（オビト）お前に
語るべきことなど何もない。
I've got nothing to say to you.
あるのは　この…　最終決戦だけだ。
All that's left...
is this final battle!
akari ga oreba kage ga dekiru to itta
You said if there's light, there are shadow
ano hi no kimi no koe ga wasure rarezu ni
I can't forget the words you said that day
tsuyoku aritai to negai
I wish to be strong
rousoku wo keshita yubi
I put out the candle with my finger
hi no watsusa ni inochi wo oboete
The heat of the flames reminded me of life
boku no koa ga hajikeru
The core of my being bursts open
guren no ai ga kokoro wo yaite
This red-hot love burns my heart
kaze ni mayoe ba namida ga ochiru
While wandering in the wind, tears start to fall
kizutsuki nagara mirai shinjite
Though I'm hurt, I believe in the future
mata saki e sono saki e
Let's go further and further ahead
gareki no sora wa bokura no kizuna
The rubble in the sky is our bond
osou mayakashi kechirashite yaru
I'll cut through the attempts to deceive me
tatakai no hate ni nani mo nakutemo
Even if there's nothing at the end of the battle
mata saki e sono saki e Ikou
Let's go further and further ahead
Kakashi's Resolve
土遁　土流壁！
Earth Style...
Mud Wall!
ウッ。
な　なぜだ。
もう口を閉じたらどうだ。
Why?
How about shutting up already?
口先だけのクズは。
You're only talk.
You're nothing but a piece of trash.
グハッ。
((俺は白い牙を
本当の英雄だと思ってる。
I believe that the White Fang
was a true hero.
確かに　忍の世界で→
Sure, in the world of Ninja,
ルールや掟を破るやつは
クズ呼ばわりされる。
one who breaks
the rules and regulations
is regarded as trash.
けどな→
But those who abandon
their comrades...
仲間を大切にしないやつは
それ以上のクズだ。
are worse than trash!
(お前が　リンを…
見殺しにしたからだろうな))
This is probably...
because you let Rin die.
（カカシ）ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
《確かに　俺はクズだ。
I am trash for sure...
だが　オビト　お前はずっと…》
But Obito, you've always...
神威！
Kamui...
《俺にとって英雄だった。
どうして…》
... been my hero.
So why?
グッ…　この！
Damn it!
あの木の野郎
九尾のチャクラを吸ってやがる！
That damned wooden thing!
It's absorbing
the Nine Tails' chakra!
クッソ…！
Damn it...
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ。
同じ眼だ。　やはり出てきたか。
We have the same eyes...
So you made it out, huh?
オビト　なぜ　そうなった。
Obito, how did you end up like this?
リンが　関係してるのか？
Does it have to do with Rin?
うっ。
((仲間は　俺が守る))
I'll protect my comrades!
((すぐにリンを助けに行くぞ))
Let's go rescue Rin right now!
((おい))
Yeah!
うわっ。
クズは　口を閉じていろと
言ったはずだ。
I said, trash should keep
their mouths shut!
死ね。
Die.
俺は　お前との約束を
守れなかった。
I... couldn't keep
my promise to you.
そう　俺は　クズだ。
You're right. I'm trash.
だが　お前は　木ノ葉の英雄だ。
But you...
You're a hero of the Leaf.
お前まで
そうなる必要はないだろ。
There's no reason for you
to become trash too.
あっ…。
クッ　ハハハッ　ハハハッ　これが現実だ。
This is reality.
託した側も　託された側も→
Those who bequeath
and the bequeathed... both.
この世界で生きながらえた忍は
皆　クズになる。
All shinobi who survive
in this world become trash.
俺たちが　いい例だ　カカシ。
You and I are prime examples,
Kakashi.
《カカシ先生》
Kakashi Sensei...
（八尾）うっ　動けねえ。
I can't move...
こいつらは　お前も邪魔だろう？
These guys are a distraction
for you too, right?
もうじき　この世界も終わる。
This world is about
to come to an end.
しばしの間　２人で楽しむために→
So in order to enjoy
the little time we've got left...
まず　戦場を
整理しておくとしよう。
Let's clear out this battlefield first.
この世界のクズを生む輪からは→
No one can escape the cycle
that gives birth to trash in this world.
皆　逃れることはできない。
だから　俺は
この世界をつくり変える。
That's why I intend
to remake the world!
おめえら　ムカつきすぎて→
You guys make me so mad,
I can't even think straight.
文句が思いつかねえ。
だから　かわりに
俺のことを　ひとつ教えておく。
So instead, let me tell you
something about myself.
俺は　クズじゃねえ。
I'm not trash!
この先　クズにもならねえ。
I'm not planning on
becoming trash either!
俺は　させねえ。
I will...
stop you!
俺の仲間は　絶対　殺させやしねえ。
- I'll never let my comrades die!
((俺の仲間は
絶対　殺させやしないよ))
I'll never let my comrades die!
《カカシ：すまん　ナルト。
I'm sorry, Naruto.
オビトの言葉を教えた俺が→
I'm the one who taught you
Obito's words, and yet...
また　ブレるところだった》
I was about to waver again.
（ガイ）昼虎。
Hirudora!
雷切。
Lightning Blade!
強がりじゃなかったな。
Guess it wasn't just a bluff.
（カカシ）オビト　かつての
お前の意志は　今でも→
Obito...
Your once strong will
is still alive today...
俺の隣にいる。
今の俺にできることは→
Right next to me!
What the current me can do
is protect the current Naruto!
今のナルトを守ることだ！
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
今のナルトを守る？
You'll protect the current Naruto?
俺も　同じくな。
Same here...
《キラービー：限界のくせしやがって。
They're both at their limits!
木ノ葉は　どいつも
強がりばっかだな》
These Hidden Leaf guys
sure love to act tough!
ん…。
木の縛りが弱まったぜ。
The wood's constriction
is weakening.
ビーのおっちゃん！
Octopops!
いてっ！　いて…。
Ow oww!
気ぃつけろ　ナルト！
敵の木遁縛りは→
Be careful, Naruto!
The enemy's Wood Paralysis is identical
to the First Hokage's!
初代　火影のと同じだ。
尾獣の力を縛る力があるぜ。
It has the power to
bind Tailed Beast Power!
ヤマト隊長のと一緒か。
Like Captain Yamato's technique...
（オビト）写輪眼　頼みの雷切→
A Lightning Blade that relies
on the Sharingan...
ずいぶん左眼を使いこなすように
なったな。
You've mastered your left eye...
万華鏡まで。
Even awakening the Mangekyo.
だが　もう一度
時空間から戻ってこれるか？
But can you make it back
from the other plane
その状態で。
in your current condition?
うっ　く…。
クズかごに入ってろ！　カカシ！
Go back to the trash heap, Kakashi!
カカシ先生も…。
Kakashi Sensei...
俺と一緒だ！
is just like... me!
そろそろ　十尾のほうも
やべえな。
Looks like we're gonna have to
start worrying about Ten Tails.
オビトってのは　あっちに任せんだ。
Let them handle Obito.
その隙に　こっちもやるぜ！
Then we'll make our move!
ヘッ！　今度は　はっきりわかんぜ。
Now I see it clearly...
てめえの苦しがるツラがよ。
your pained face.
（オビト）そんなセリフは　隣のやつを見て
言ったらどうだ？
Save those lines for
the one right next to you.
ハァ　ハァ…。
《確かに　カカシ先生を
なんとかしねえと。
I definitely have to help
Kakashi Sensei somehow.
写輪眼の使いすぎで
バッテバテになってるし→
He's completely drained from
overusing the Sharingan.
もう　吸い込まれたら…》
If he gets sucked in...
（九喇嘛）ナルト　少し代われ。
Naruto, switch with me...
え？
ここは　わしにやらせろ。
Huh?
Let me handle this.
でも…。
いいから代われ！
But...
Don't argue. Just switch!
（九喇嘛）おい　カカシのガキ　手ぇ出せ。
Hey, Kakashi brat,
give me your hands...
お前は…。
You're...
（九喇嘛）いいから　早く手ぇ出せ！
Never mind that!
Just stick out your hands!
うわぁ　アホ！　九喇嘛！
なんてことしてんだよ！
Kurama! What the hell
did you just do?
これで気がねなくやれる。
Now you don't have any distractions.
あとは任せたぞ　ナルト。
I'm leaving the rest to you, Naruto.
はぁ！？
What?!
くっそ！！
Damn!
能力がわかってる分→
Now that we know how
your ability works, I can counter it.
注意してれば反撃できる。
更に　もう１発！
Here's another!
ああ
確かに苦しそうなツラだな　オビト。
Oh yeah, that certainly
is a pained face Obito.
何だ！？
What's going on?
向こうのカカシがやったんだ。
Kakashi did that. Over there.
お前と　わしの違いはな→
The difference between
you and me is...
チャクラの受け渡しが
自由にできるってことだ。
I can give or take chakra
voluntarily at will.
またあとで
お前にもコツを教えてやる。
I'll show you how it's done later.
いつ渡したの？
When did you pass it to him?
カカシをぶん投げようと
手をつかんだときだ。
When I grabbed his hand
to throw him.
じゃあ…。
もちろん。
So then...!
Yeah, whenever he wants to,
いつでも　神威で出てこられる。
he can use Kamui to come out.
カカシ先生！
Kakashi Sensei!
（カカシ）九尾に礼を言っといてくれ。
Thank Nine Tails for me.
あぁ！
Sure!
復活する前に　チリヂリに吹き飛ばす！
Let's blast him to bits
before he revives!
ありったけ　ためろ！
おう。
Put in everything you've got!
Right!
もう行けっぜ！
ビーのおっちゃんに　八っつぁん。
It's ready to go,
Octopops and Eight-o!
よし！　うて！！
Okay!
Fire!
これで　終わりだ！！
It's over now!
魔像のチャクラが…　消えた！
The Statue's chakra... is gone.
やった！
We did it.
やったんだよ。
バカヤロー　このヤロー！
We did it, fool! Ya fool!
よっしゃあ～！！
All right then!
終わった…　のか？
It's over?
ああ…　この世界がな。
Yeah... for this world.
さてと…。
Now then...
始めるか…。
Shall we get started?
kidzuite ndaro sou sekai ga kataru itsuwari to
I'm sure you've realized by now that the world tells lies
amai wana ni soko ni wa hontou nante nai koto o
And lays alluring traps, but there's no truth behind them
riyuu sagashite run away why? sono mewotojiteru no?
Search for a reason Run away Why?
Why are you closing your eyes?
tell me why can't you
Tell me why can't you
shinjitsu ni te o nobase!
Reach out for the truth!
always (sakebe shout out) all time (tsukame catch up)
Always (Scream, Shout out)
All the time (Catch it, Catch up)
everybody knows (we are the seeker get fire!!!)
Everybody knows (We are the seeker Get fire!!!)
moyase moyase kokoro no honou
Burn, burn the fire in your heart
tsuyoku aritai to negau nonaraba
if you firmly wish for it
narase narase mezame no kane o
Ring, ring the bell of awakening
koyoi tsuki no shita de kokoro sakebe
Shout from your heart under the moon tonight
utae utae hoero hoero
Sing, sing, howl, howl,
kibou no hikari o nozomu nonaraba
if you want the light of hope
moyase moyase kokoro no honou
Burn, burn the fire in your heart
akai tsuki no shita de kimi o sakebe
Shout to you under the red moon
ima ima ima flame up (catch the fire)
Now, now, now, Flame up (Catch the fire)
ima ima ima flame up (blaze up!!!)
Now, now, now, Flame up (Blaze up!!!)
Here comes a big one,
you think we can really do this?
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
First, we keep our distance
and see what move he makes.
美空ひばりです。
Then we'll counter the attack
and hit him
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
with a big blow
as close as we can get.
お楽しみください。
Nine Tails, you're acting
like a captain.
So? You got a problem with that?
Nope. In fact I feel kinda happy!
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Allied Shinobi Forces Jutsu"
今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手の
皆さんによる→
華麗なステージを
お届けいたします。
Save that line for after we've won!